

Bangalore, India

□ (+91) 82-4015-9173 | 🗷 alokr417@gmail.com | 🌴 alokraj.me | 🖸 alok722 | 🛅 alok722 | 💆 @alok722 | 📢 alok722 |

"To Learn, To Earn & Be Valuable."

Summary_

Current Web UI Developer at Globant with 3+ years of experience specializing in JavaScript technologies. A Super nerd who loves JavaScript & its frameworks, libraries and enjoys customizing all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Experience

Globant Bangalore, India

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER (WEB UI DEVELOPER)

Mar. 2021 - present

- Have been working and leading development of cross frameworks UI library using StencilJS.
- Have been working extensively on Banking web application and making it accessible
- Been part of project right from discovery phase and led the development of initial phase of Micro Front-end Apps with React.Js using Module Federation Approach in Design/Build phase.
- Mentoring freshers and colleagues on new javascript technologies as part of Globant's studio initiative.
- Tech stacks: React. Js with Typescript & Redux, RxJS, StencilJS, CSS Modules, SCSS, React Testing Library, Jest, i18n

Tata Consultancy Services

Bangalore, India

June 2019 - Mar. 2021

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (MERN STACK DEVELOPER)

- Implemented a scheduler jobs microservice using Node, Express & MongoDB to automate the manual process of data sync and notification service, also an **ReactJS** app to display the success/failure of Jobs.
- Developed an easy-to-use SMTP RESTful API server replicating AWS SES template system using NodeJS, ExpressJs & MongoDB which is being consumed by different projects within org.
- Implemented Dynamic form template system using the MERN stack which helped reduce development time approximately by 15%.
- Developed a Mongo migration utility web-app to help with data administration tasks using vanilla JavaScript as a POC.
- · Been part of TCS internal web-app developement using the MEAN stack to manage client's projects, allocated resources and Billing related accounts.
- Tech stacks: ReactJS, Angular 7+, Angular Material, RxJS, Node.Js, Express.Js, MongoDB, Microservice arch., Mocha, Chai

GroupClap EdTech Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

Customer facing WordPress and static websites using HTML, CSS & Javascript.

- Developed a web app POC to replicate some of the functionalities of Zomato's website.
- Developed the official Android app of GroupClap using Android's Web View.
- Tech stacks: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress, Android, PHP.

Vedas Technocrats Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India

Feb. 2018 - June 2018

INTERN

• Developed front-end of multiple Android apps as per client's requirement.

- Integrated and consumed APIs & SDKs to make Android apps more functional.
- Tech stack: Android.

Skills_

Front-end React.js, Vue.js, Angular 2+, StencilJS, Redux, RxJs, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Material UI, Vuetify, Angular Material

Back-end NodeJs, ExpressJs Language JavaScript, TypeScript **Database** MongoDB (Mongoose), MS-SQL

Basic Docker, PWA, Web accessibility, Git & GitHub, JSDoc & TSDoc, Unit Testing (Mocha, Jest), Open source enthusiast, AGILE Others

methodologies

Soft-skills Excellent communication skill, Team Work Spirit, Leadership skill

Education

MCKV Institute of Engineering

Kolkata, India

B. TECH. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug. 2015 - June 2019

• A graduate with an aggregate of 8.08 CGPA having good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle.

JANUARY 15, 2022 ALOK RALL . CURRICULUM VITAF



Care for the Living April 2021 - PRESENT

CORE MEMBER

- It is a **open-source** project that started with a motive to help and provide vital information to **Covid-19 crisis** needy.
- It is a platform where we are connecting requestor to donor with the help of many volunteers.
- **Tech Stacks**: React.js, TypeScript, Recoil.js, Material UI, Firebase

Open Devs Jun. 2020 - PRESENT

CO-CREATOR

- Open devs is an organization created by motivated developers who love building different open source software to contribute & give back to the community.
- Tech Stacks: Full Stack JavaScript frameworks & libraries.

Portfolio Aug. 2020 - PRESENT

CREATOR

- A web app to showcase my experience, education, skill-set, projects, certificates, achievements, recommendations & more in an organized manner.
- Tech Stacks: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, PWA.

Relax a Little - VS Code Extension

Oct. 2020

CO-CREATOR

- This extension provides tools to relax like giving reminders to look somewhere else, drink water, walk, do some lunges or best of all, slowly fades out the colors until you take your hands off the keyboard for a moment. comes with lot of configurations to control time of reminder, interval, water drinking intervals, generic break alert and more.
- Tech Stack: JavaScript, chroma-js, npm.

Others @GitHub 2017 - PRESENT

CREATOR

• Many other small & medium level 60+ projects are available at my github repository.

Activities & Achievements

Co-Founder, Creator of Open Source Software Development Team (opendevs) with **5** open source projects

- 2021 relax-a-little (VS Code Extension, **200+** downloads), fastify-typescript-generator (**500+** weekly downloads on npm), express-boilerplate-generator, s3-bucket-downloader & others.
- 2021 **Recognition**, Received 3 fantabulous awards within 10 months at Globant.
- 2021 Instructor, Acted as a Instructor & trained peer associates on MongoDB during my tenure at TCS
- 2021 **Tech Bairn,** Gave training to 30+ students on MERN stack along with my friend as opendevs initiative
- 2020 **Recognition,** Even being a fresher, I surpassed many expectations & got recognized with many accolades like Special Achievement, On the Spot, Star of the Month, Best Team Award during my tenure at TCS.
- Blogs, YDKJS UP & GOING, Takeaways for Experienced JavaScript Developer | Story of Transition to the Senior SE role | Road-map to becoming Web Developer
- 2019 **Position of Responsibility,** Held several positions of responsibilities like: Class Representative, Anti ragging cell member, Placement cell member during college.
- Project Leader, Lead a team of 4 for an Android project called AVRIK People safety app which later won the 1st position in intra-college technical exhibition.
- Project Leader, Lead a team of 3 for a PHP project called Online FIR management system which was awarded as the Best project of semester break training program.

JANUARY 15, 2022 ALOK RAJ · CURRICULUM VITAE